(630) 384-9402 jacobdavidson79@gmail.com Jacobmdavidson.com

Summary

A driven .NET developer with experience in a wide range of Microsoft technologies. An enthusiastic high achiever with a passion for continuous learning.

Core Technical Skills

.Net Technologies and Languages: ADO.NET, ASP.NET, C#, Entity Framework, MVC, SignalR, VB.NET, Web Forms, Xamarin

Web Technologies and Languages: AJAX, Angular, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, JSON, jQuery, PHP, XML **Database Management Systems:** MySQL, MS SQL Server

Development Tools: SQL Server Management Studio, Team Foundation Server, Visual Studio IDE, Visual Studio Code **Azure Cloud Services:** Application Insights, App Service, Content Delivery Network, Service Bus, SQL Database, Storage **Web Servers:** IIS, Apache

Experience

Programmer

• American Academy of Sleep Medicine

Darien, IL

01/2016 - Present

- Overhauled a legacy web application dedicated to improving sleep study scoring consistency for sleep technologists. This ASP.NET Web Forms application was developed using VB.NET, ADO.NET, and MS SQL Server.
 - * Upgraded the administrative dashboard to a customized version of Bootstrap 3.
 - * Developed an internal notification system to reduce reliance on external emails.
 - * Integrated with amCharts for better graphical representation of collected data.
 - * Migrated from Telerik reporting to jsreports for deeper report customization.
 - * Simplified the registration and subscription processes.
- Provided ongoing maintenance and developed new features for the professional version of the AASM SleepTM telemedicine platform built with ASP.NET Web Forms. This n-tiered application was created using VB.NET, ADO.NET, MS SQL Server, SignalR, and WebRTC.
 - * Integrated Stripe Connect to allow users to accept client payments.
 - * Created a medical history collection component with a Clinical Document Architecture Release 2 formatted export feature.
 - * Migrated static content to a CDN.
 - * Implemented an Azure Service Bus backplane to facilitate seamless application deployment slot swapping without severing SignalR connections.
- Designed and implemented a lightweight version of the AASM SleepTM telemedicine platform with ASP.NET MVC 5 using C#, Entity Framework 6, SignalR, MS SQL Server, and WebRTC.
- Developed Android and iOS applications that integrate with the AASM SleepTM telemedicine platform using Xamarin.Android, Xamarin.iOS, SignalR, and WebRTC.
- Provided ongoing maintenance for a console based VB.NET application that uses XSLT transformations to convert XML into HTML for both web-based and Kindle publications.

Freelance Web Developer

Glen Ellyn, IL

Web developer for various clients

06/2012 - 06/2014

Education

• University of Illinois at Springfield

M.S. Computer Science (GPA: 4.0 out of 4.0)

Purdue University

M.S. Civil Engineering (GPA: 4.0 out of 4.0)

Oregon State University

B.S. Civil Engineering (GPA: 3.89 out of 4.0)

Springfield, IL 08/2013 – 12/2015 West Lafayette, IN 08/2003 – 12/2004 Corvallis, OR

09/1998 - 03/2003

Project Highlights

Sleep ISR Upgrade

isr.aasm.org

ADO.NET, ASP.NET 4.0, MS SQL Server, VB.NET, Web Forms

05/2018-Present

A web application dedicated to improving sleep study scoring consistency for sleep technologists (upgrade launched: 09/04/2018).

AASM SleepTM Android App

play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.aasm.sleeptm

Xamarin.Android, C#, SignalR, WebRTC

08/2017-Present

An Android application that integrates with the AASM SleepTM telemedicine platform allowing patients to engage in telemedicine encounters using an Android device (launched: 09/11/2017).

AASM SleepTM iOS App

itunes.apple.com/us/app/aasm-sleeptm/id1253586517?mt=8

Xamarin.iOS, C#, SignalR, WebRTC

04/2017 - Present

An iOS application that integrates with the AASM SleepTM telemedicine platform allowing patients to engage in telemedicine encounters using an iOS device (launched: 07/31/2017).

AASM SleepTM Select

sleeptm.com/

ASP.NET 4.5, C#, Entity Framework 6, MS SQL Server, MVC5, SignalR, WebRTC

10/2016-Present

A light weight version of the AASM SleepTM sleep-specific telemedicine platform that focuses on a simplified telemedicine encounter process (launched: 04/20/2017).

AASM SleepTM Pro

sleeptm.com/

ADO.NET, ASP.NET 4.5, MS SQL Server, SignalR, VB.NET, Web Forms, WebRTC

01/2016-Present

A full featured, HIPAA compliant telemedicine platform developed specifically for sleep doctors.

Elavon Converge Payment Gateway for WooCommerce

jacobmdavidson.com/converge/

PHP, WooCommerce, WordPress

09/2012-10/2016

WordPress plugin that adds a Converge payment gateway to WooCommerce (an eCommerce solution for WordPress).

• Professional Engineering License Manager

jacobmdavidson.com/pelicensemanager/

Joomla, MySQL, PHP

08/2012-02/2018

Membership based web application built on the Joomla content management system that helps engineers manage continuing education requirements for professional engineering licenses.

Computer SMS Android and Desktop Applications

jacobmdavidson.com/computersms/

Android, Java

10/2015

Send and receive SMS text messages through an Android phone using a desktop application connected to the same local area network. Includes multicast DNS to simplify service discovery, XML message passing, and AES-128 message encryption derived from a Diffie-Hellman key exchange.

Surveying Coordinate Transformation

jacobmdavidson.com/coordinate-transformation/

C#.NET

08/2014

Created for the survey department of Patrick Engineering, Inc., this WPF application transforms survey coordinates from one coordinate system to another using the least squares methodology.

SMorSe for Android

jacobmdavidson.com/smorse/

Android, Java

07/2014

Converts incoming SMS text messages to Morse code based on the ITU-RM.1667-1 recommendation, and plays or vibrates the message in accordance with the volume settings of the phone.